Guide to the Edward Weber Allen Papers 1886-1975
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Edward Weber Allen papers
1886-1975
1929-1974
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0129
0129-003
Allen, Edward Weber, 1885-1976
35.46 cubic feet
Papers of Edward Allen, an attorney, fisheries expert, and commissioner of the International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission.
Edward Weber Allen (1885-1976) was an attorney from Seattle, Washington, who specialized in fisheries law. Beginning in 1928, he represented Alaska salmon packers in many capacities, including legal affairs, labor matters, lobbying, and as public spokesman for the industry. The following is a list of organizations to which he belonged or by which he was employed, and their function:
Canned Salmon Industry Inc. (advertising, etc.),
Alaska Salmon Industry Inc. (industry representatives in labor negotiations, etc.),
Pacific Fisheries Conference (Allen was vice chairman),
Alaska Salmon Institute Northwest Salmon Canners Association (trade group), and
American Salmon Protective Committee Association of Pacific Fisheries (research organization).
Allen also used his knowledge of fisheries law to the benefit of various international commissions. He was a member from 1932 to 1955 of the International Fisheries Commission (known after 1953 as the International Pacific Halibut Commission), and also served as its chairman and secretary. The International Fisheries Commission helped restore the depleted halibut stocks in the North Pacific. Allen also served as a commissioner of the International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission from 1937 to 1957, which was formed to revive the salmon stock of the Puget Sound and Fraser River. In 1954 Allen helped create the International North Pacific Fisheries Commission, which was composed of representatives of the United States, Canada, and Japan. The commission met every three years and Allen served as chairman. He was also a long-time member of the U.S. State Department Fishing Industry Advisory Committee.
Additionally, Allen was active in the American Bar Association. He chaired its Law of the Sea Committee and served on its International and Comparative Law Section, as well as other committees. During World War II Allen served in the United States Office of Strategic Services.
In 1957 Allen was named Puget Sound Maritime Man of the Year. In 1959 he received the Raymond J. Huff Memorial Award for service in the field of international affairs.
Allen was the author of four books: North Pacific: Japan, Siberia, Alaska, Canada (1936), which attempted to raise the alarm about Japanese fishing in the North Pacific; Dancing Tails and Other Fishy Jingles (1951) – a collection of his poems; The Vanishing Frenchman: The Mysterious Disappearance of Lapérouse (1959); and Lapérouse: A Check List (1959).
Contains correspondence, writings, reports, proceedings, and related items documenting Allen's work as a fisheries expert. The Fishing Commissions series includes records from Allen's work with the International Fisheries Commission, the International Pacific Halibut Commission, the International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission, and the International North Pacific Fisheries Commission. The Law Organizations series includes records from various law associations and foundations, such as committees of the American Bar Association on which Allen served. The Other Organizations series includes records from other organizations or associations, many relating to fishing, in which Allen was active. Examples include the Institute of Pacific Relations, Pacific Northwest Division. The Law and Consulting Practice series bring together records of Allen's work as a long time representative of the Alaska salmon packing industry. This series includes records from Allen's work in various capacities with multiple corporate entities over a period of nearly forty years, including the Law of the Sea Institute. The Personal Papers series largely contains miscellaneous files that did not fit into the other series.
Arranged in 5 series:
Fishing Commissions, 1926-1974
Law Organizations, 1929-1973
Other Organizations, 1937-1971
Law and Consulting Practice, 1886-1974 (bulk 1934-1972)
Personal Papers, 1929-1975
The papers are open to all users.
Gift of Edward Allen, 1960-1969, 1978.
Allen, Edward Weber, 1885-1976--Archives; Bartlett, Edward Lewis, 1904-1968; Bennett, Eugene D. (Eugene Dunlap), 1894-1968; Bingham, Joseph Walter, 1878-1973; Bishop, William W. (William Warner), 1906-; Brooding, Milton E.; Chapman, Wilbert McLeod, 1910-1970; Freeman, Miller, 1875-1955; Herrington, William C. (William Charles), 1903-; Jackson, Charles E.; Jackson, Henry M. (Henry Martin), 1912-1983; Johansen, George; Magnuson, Warren Grant, 1905-; Moran, Robert, 1857-1943; Pelly, Thomas M. (Thomas Minor), 1902-1973; Tollefson, Thor C. (Thor Carl), 1901-
American Bar Association; Institute of Pacific Relations. American Council. Pacific Northwest Division; Law of the Sea Institute; Pacific Northwest Trade Association; United Nations Conference on the Law of the Sea; United States. Dept. of State; United States. Dept. of State. Fishing Industry Advisory Committee; United States. Office of Strategic Services; Association of Pacific Fisheries; International Fisheries Commission; International North Pacific Fisheries Commission; International Pacific Halibut Commission; International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission; Washington State Bar Association
United States--Economic policy--1933-1945; United States--Foreign relations--20th century; United States--Politics and government--20th century
Authors, American--Washington (State)--Seattle--Archives; Collective bargaining--Fisheries; Fish trade--Law and legislation; Fish trade--Law and legislation--Washington (State); Fisheries--Societies, etc.; Fisheries--Alaska; Fisheries--Japan; Fisheries--North Pacific Ocean; Fisheries--North Pacific Ocean--Statistics; Fisheries--North Pacific Ocean--Societies, etc.; Fishery law and legislation--Congresses; Fishery law and legislation--Alaska; Fishery law and legislation--North Pacific Ocean; Fishery law and legislation--Northwest, Pacific; Fishery management, International--North Pacific Ocean; Fishery consultants--Washington (State)--Seattle--Archives; Halibut industry--North Pacific Ocean; Indians of North America--Fishing--Alaska; Law of the sea; Law--Societies, etc.; Lawyers--Washington (State)--Seattle--Archives; Pacific halibut fisheries; Pacific salmon fisheries; Salmon canning industry--Alaska; Salmon industry--North Pacific Ocean
Fisheries and Wildlife; Fishing and Canning; International Relations; Washington (State)
annual reports; articles; Bills, legislative; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); correspondence; financial records; Memorandums; minutes; Newsletters; Press releases; proceedings; regulations; reports; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Treaties; writings
Dancing tails and other fishy jingles; North Pacific: Japan, Siberia, Alaska, Canada; The vanishing Frenchman: the mysterious disappearance of Lapérouse
- Fishing Commissions, 1926-1974
  - International Fisheries Commission
    Became the International Pacific Halibut Commission in November 1953.
    - General Correspondence
      - 1932-1941 (Box-folder 1/1-1/18)
      - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1a/1-38)
      - 1943-1953 (Box-folder 2/1-9)
    - Organizational Materials, undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Speeches and Writings by Allen, undated (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Memoranda Concerning North Pacific Fish, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Reports Concerning Fisheries, 1929, 1933, 1952 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Pacific Halibut Fishery Regulations, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Treaties, 1926-1949 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Court Cases -- Canada, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Halibut Newsletters, November 1946-October 1948 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Circulars, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Miscellaneous -- Papers, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 2/21)
  - International Pacific Halibut Commission
    - General Correspondence, September 1953-1955, 1961 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Organization/History, undated (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Reports, 1953-1957, 1959 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1961, undated (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Clippings, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - International Pacific Salmon Fisheries Commission
    - General Correspondence
      - 1937-1940 (Box-folder 2/27-62)
      - 1941-1945 February (Box-folder 3/1-45)
      - 1945 March-1950 (Box-folder 4/1-37)
      - 1951-1960 (Box-folder 5/1-6)
    - Correspondence Regarding:
      - Selective Service Deferment for James E. Mason, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - Selective Service Deferment for Leslie E. Whitesel, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Organizational Information, undated (Box-folder 5/9)
    - United States Canada Sockeye Salmon Convention, 1930-1957 (Box-folder 5/10-11)
    - Minutes, 1937-1957 (Box-folder 5/12-16)
    - Appropriations, 1944-1950 (Box-folder 5/17-19)
    - Budgets, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 5/20-21)
    - Annual Reports, 1939-1950 (Box-folder 5/22-25)
    - Memoranda
      - Regarding Commission Meetings and Policies, 1941-1948, undated (Box-folder 5/26)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1951, undated (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Reports
      - Regarding Thompson River, 1946 (Box-folder 5/28)
        - The Biological Basis for Regulation, 1948 (Box-folder 5/29)
        - Red Salmon, 1959, undated (Box-folder 5/30-31)
        - Chilko River Watershed, 1949 (Box-folder 5/32)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940-1958, undated (Box-folder 5/33-37)
    - Fishery Regulations, 1946-1952, undated (Box-folder 5/38-39)
    - Treaty, 1937 (Box-folder 5/40)
    - Information Regarding Sockeye Salmon, 1933-1957, undated (Box-folder 6/1-4)
    - Speeches and Writings of Others, undated (Box-folder 6/5-6)
    - Published Articles, 1941-1950 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Contracts and Agreements, 1942, 1944, 1946 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Exchequer Court Petitions -- Coast Construction Company, Ltd., 1947-1948 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Bills and Acts, 1930-1957 (Box-folder 6/11-12)
    - Resolutions
      - Passed at Commission Meetings, 1937-1948 (Box-folder 6/13)
      - Miscellaneous, 1944-1948, undated (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Catch Statistics, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 6/15-16)
    - Programs, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Progress Reports, 1951 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Briefs, 1937-1949 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Miscellany -- Writings and Photographs, 1947-1955, undated (Box-folder 6/20)
    - News Releases, 1949-1951, undated (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Subject Files -- Hell's Gate
      - Memoranda and Statistics, 1942 (Box-folder 6/24)
      - Report, 1942 (Box-folder 6/25)
      - Memoranda and Graphs, 1945, undated (Box-folder 6/26)
      - Articles and Clippings, 1941-1946 (Box-folder 6/28)
      - Writings
        - William Thompson and William Ricker, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 6/30)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 6/31)
      - Photographs, Maps and Graphs, undated (Box-folder 6/32)
    - Proceedings of Commission Meetings
      - 1943-1947 (Box-folder 6/33-37)
      - 1948-1967 (Box-folder 7/1-12)
  - International North Pacific Fisheries Commission
    - Organizational Features, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - General Correspondence, 1953-1974 (Box-folder 7/14-24, 8/1-29, 9/1-32)
    - Telegrams, 1972-1973
    - United States State Department, undated (Box-folder 9/32-33)
    - Memoranda and Statements, undated (Box-folder 9/35)
    - Meetings and Proceedings, 1954-1974 (Box-folder 10/1-21)
      Includes proceedings, agendas, speeches, memos, correspondence, writings, etc.
    - Financial Records, 1955-1956, 1973 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Reports
      - Annual Report, 1955 (Box-folder 10/23)
      - Ad Hoc Committee, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 10a/1)
      - Alaska Salmon Stocks, probably 1955 (Box-folder 10a/2)
      - Canadian Fisheries and Fishery Research, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 10a/3)
      - Executive Director, 1955, 1957 (Box-folder 10a/4)
      - First Meeting, 1954 (Box-folder 10a/5)
      - Investigation by United States for International North Pacific Fisheries Commission, 1955-1957, 1973 (Box-folder 11/1-4)
      - Japanese Fisheries and Salmon Research, 1955-1958, 1973 (Box-folder 11/5)
      - Pacific Salmon Investigations, 1956 (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Parasite Studies of Sockeye and Pink Salmon, 1956 (Box-folder 11/7)
      - Researches on Salmon, 1955, 1958, 1960 (Box-folder 11/8)
      - To United States Section by W. F. Thompson, 1960 (Box-folder 11/9)
      - Visit to Alaska, 1956 (Box-folder 11/10)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Edward W. Allen, 1954-1965, undated (Box-folder 11/12-13)
      - Others, 1952-1965, 1972, undated (Box-folder 11/14-15)
      - Regarding Abstention (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Bills and Acts, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Treaties, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Newsletters, 1954-1971 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - News Releases, 1953-1970 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Publications, 1957-1964, 1974, undated (Box-folder 11/21-23)
    - Notes, 1957-1958, undated (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Ephemera, 1949-1957 (Box-folder 11/25)
    - Research Programs, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 11/26)
    - Lists, 1954, 1957, 1972 (Box-folder 11/27)
    - Maps, 1956 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - Photographs, 1971, undated (Box-folder 11/29)
    - Clippings, 1953-1972 (Box-folder 11/30-32)
    - Subject Files
      - Fishery Statistics, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 11/33)
      - Japan -- Soviet Fisheries Treaty and Commission, 1957, 1964 (Box-folder 11/34)
      - New Zealand (Box-folder 11/35)
      - Pacific Coast Fishery Regulations, 1954 (Box 12)
      - United Nations International Law Commission, 1956, undated (Box 12)
      - United States -- USSR North Pacific Fishery Negotiations, 1971 (Box 12)
- Law Organizations, 1929-1973
  - American Bar Association, International and Comparative Law Section Correspondence
    - 1941-1945 (Box 12)
    - 1946-1947, 1952-1968 (Box 13)
    - 1968-1973 (Box 14)
  - American Bar Association, Law of the Sea Committee Correspondence, 1963-1965, 1966 (Box 15)
  - American Bar Association, Oceanography Committee Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - American Bar Association, Peace And Law Committee Correspondence, Reports, and Related Items, 1952-1953 (Box 15)
  - American Bar Association, World Peace Through Law Committee Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 15)
  - American Bar Association, Commerce Committee Correspondence, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Bar Association, Miscellaneous Records (Box 16)
  - American Bar Foundation Correspondence, 1964-1973 (Box 15)
  - Seattle Bar Association, International and Comparative Law Section Correspondence, 1959 (Box 15)
  - American Law Institute Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 15)
  - International Law Association, 1958-1960 (Box 15)
  - Pacific Northwest Trade Association Correspondence, 1953-1960 (Box 15)
  - Washington State Bar Association
    - General Correspondence, 1929 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-1966 (Box 16-17)
- Other Organizations, 1937-1971
  - Association of Pacific Fisheries Correspondence, 1961-1967 (Box 17)
  - Alaska Salmon Institute Articles of Incorporation and Financial Statement, 1952 (Box 17)
  - Alaska Salmon Protective Committee Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 17)
    Formerly known as the Alaska Salmon Institute.
  - United States Strategic Service Office Correspondence, Reports, and Other Material, 1941-1949 (Box 17)
  - United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization Correspondence and Other Material, 1948-1950 (Box 18)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, Northwest Branch, undated (Box 18)
  - Marine Technology Society Correspondence, Newsletters, and Other Material, 1966-1968 (Box 18)
  - Joint Public Information Committee, undated (Box 27)
  - United States Fisheries Mission to Japan, 1949 (Box 27)
  - United States State Department, Fishing Industry Advisory Committee, 1937-1970 (Box 27)
  - Seattle Chamber of Commerce, Alaska Division, undated (Box 27)
  - Mountaineers, undated (Box 27)
  - Rainier Club Library Committee, 1966-1971 (Box 27)
  - Navy League of the United States, 1966-1971 (Box 27)
- Law and Consulting Practice, 1886-1974; 1934-1972
  - General Correspondence
    - 1934-1964 (Box 19)
    - 1965-1974, undated (Box 20)
  - General Correspondence Regarding: (Box 20)
    - Alaska Salmon Industry Inc., 1941-1942, 1953-1957 (Box 20)
    - Territorial Waters and Protection of Coastal Fishers (Pacific Fisheries Conference and Canned Salmon Industry), 1953-1956 (Box 20)
      Includes writings.
    - United States State Department, Pacific Fisheries Conference, 1948 (Box 20)
  - General Correspondence (Box 21)
    The following correspondents may also be represented in the chronological correspondence in boxes 19 and 20.
    - Bartlett, T. L., 1963-1966 (Box 21)
    - Bartlett, T. L. (Bob) and Haakon B. Friele, 1964-1968 (Box 21)
    - Chapman, Wilbert, 1952-1970, undated (Box 21)
    - Freeman, Miller, 1942-1945 (Box 21)
    - Johansen, George, 1954-1963, undated (Box 21)
    - Magnuson, Warren, 1954-1955, 1963-1969 (Box 21)
    - Nakat Packing Corporation (Haakon B. Friele), 1928-1929, 1945-1967, undated (Box 21)
    - Rhode Island University, Law of the Sea Institute, 1965-1974 (Box 21)
    - United States State Department, undated (Box 21)
  - Incoming Letters (Box 21)
    - Johnson, Ralph W., 1967 (Box 21)
      Includes a report.
    - Concerning Article by Allen, 1946 (Box 21)
  - Labor Negotiations
    - Herring Fisherman, 1934-1939, undated (Box 21)
    - Cannery Workers, 1938-1939 (Box 21)
    - Reduction Workers, 1937 (Box 21)
    - Salmon Industry, 1934, 1937, 1939 (Box 21)
    - Labor Data, 1937-1938 (Box 21)
    - Washington Packers, 1938 (Box 21)
    - Fact Finding Committee, 1938 (Box 21)
    - Union Organizations, 1938 (Box 21)
    - Agreements -- Wage Contracts, 1935-1937 (Box 21)
  - Subject Files
    - Advertising, 1937-1938, 1940-1941 (Box 21)
    - Alaska Indian Hearings, circa 1942-1946; 27 folders (Box 21)
    - Alaska Salmon Industry, Inc., 1940-1943 (Box 22)
    - Canada -- 12 Mile Zone, circa 1962-1966 (Box 22)
    - Canned Salmon Industry, 1934-1943, undated (Box 22)
    - Caribbean Commission, 1946-1947 (Box 22)
    - Congressional Resolutions Concerning United Nations Control of Ocean Floor, 1967-1968 (Box 22)
    - Dams, 1955 (Box 22)
    - Fish Traps, 1940 (Box 22)
    - International Boundary and Water Commission, 1946-1947 (Box 22)
    - International Joint Commission, 1935-1950 (Box 22)
    - Japan, 1926-1936 (Box 22)
    - Japan -- Alaska Fisheries, undated (Box 23)
    - Japanese Fishing, 1934-1967 (Box 23)
    - Japanese Treaty, 1949-1952 (Box 23)
    - Law of the Sea, undated (Box 23)
    - Maslenikov Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 23)
    - New Fishery Law Drafts, 1941 (Box 23)
    - Pacific Fisheries Conference, 1946-1963 (Box 23)
    - Research, 1944 (Box 23)
    - Schwellenbach, Hull Proclamation, undated (Box 23)
    - State Compacts, Fisheries, 1940 (Box 23)
    - Steamship Freight Rates, undated (Box 23)
    - Treaty Reservations, 1958-1959 (Box 23)
    - Tripartite Negotiations for North Pacific Fisheries Convention, 1951 (Box 23)
    - Truman Proclamation, 1945 (Box 23)
    - United Nations, 1965-1967 (Box 23)
  - Conferences and Conventions
    - American Wildlife Institute, 1944 (Box 23)
    - Conference on Pink Salmon of the Fraser River Area, 1956 (Box 23)
    - Expert Meeting on Fishery Statistics in the North Atlantic Area, 1959 (Box 23)
    - International Commission for the North Atlantic Fisheries, 1967 (Box 23)
    - North Atlantic Fisheries Conference, 1952 (Box 23)
    - North American Wildlife Conference, 1941-1946 (Box 23)
    - University of Michigan Law School, Institute of International Law, undated (Box 23)
    - United Nations International Technical Conference on the Conservation of the Living Resources of the Sea, 1955 (Box 23)
    - United Nations Law of the Sea Conferences, 1956-1972 (Box 23-24)
    - International Convention for the High Seas Fisheries of the North Pacific Coast, Ottawa, 1963-1964 (Box 24)
    - European Fisheries Conference, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Conference on the Future of the United States Fishing Industry, Seattle, 1968 (Box 24)
    - First Latin American Congress of Oceanography, Marine Biology and Fisheries, 1941 (Box 24)
    - United Nations Committee on the Peaceful Uses of the Seabed and the Ocean Floor, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous Conventions, undated (Box 24)
  - List of Edward Allen Articles, undated (Box 24)
  - Writings -- Publications with Allen Articles, 1937-1951, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Writings -- Clippings of Allen Articles, 1929-1968 (Box 24)
  - Writings -- Miscellaneous, 1938-1967, undated (Box 25)
  - Writings
    - Book Reviews, 1946-1966, undated (Box 25)
    - "Who Owns the Deep Blue Sea?", 1967 (Box 25)
    - "Freedom of the Sea", 1966 (Box 25)
    - "How Many Fish in the Sea?", 1941 (Box 25)
    - "Law, Fish and Policy", probably 1971 (Box 25)
  - Writings -- Notes and Fragments, undated (Box 25)
  - Speeches, 1944-1965 (Box 25)
  - Writings of Others
    - Miscellaneous, 1937-1970, undated (Box 25)
    - Kratz, Jeremiah, 1963 (Box 25)
    - Chapman, Wilbert, 1947-1969 (Box 25)
  - Speeches of Others, 1947-1966 (Box 25)
  - Reports
    - International Law Commission, 1950-1956 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1970 (Box 26)
  - Government Hearings, 1933, 1954, 1963 (Box 26)
  - Bills, 1941-1943 (Box 26)
  - Congressional Record -- Tear Sheets, undated (Box 26)
  - Court Papers, 1941, 1945 (Box 26)
  - Fish Treaties, 1886, 1923-1967 (Box 26)
  - Fishery Statistics, 1943-1966 (Box 26)
  - Chronologies, 1911, 1928 (Box 26)
  - Newsletters and Mailings, 1938-1973 (Box 26)
  - News Releases, 1938-1945, 1957 (Box 26)
  - Clippings
    - Concerning Allen, 1936-1972 (Box 26)
    - Concerning Fisheries and Fish, 1935-1972 (Box 26)
    - Stan Patty Articles, 1958, 1967 (Box 26)
  - Ephemera, 1935-1951, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1956 (Box 26)
  - Newspapers and Publications, 1934-1969 (Box 26)
- Personal Papers, 1929-1975
  - Biographical Features, undated (Box 27)
  - General Correspondence
    Arranged chronologically.
    Correspondents include:
    Adams, Russell B., 1955, 1956
    The Alaska Sportsman, 1935
    Alaska, State of, 1962, 1971
    Alaska State Federation of Fishermen's Association, 1969
    Alaska Steamship Company, 1932, 1933
    Albertson, A. H., 1933, 1961
    Albright, Horace M., 1933
    Alexander, G. F, 1934
    Alexander, Lewis M., 1970
    Allen, Raymond B., 1948
    Allen, Riley H., 1954, 1955, 1956, 1957, 1961, 1962, 1963, 1966
    Allman, Ruth, 1957, 1959, 1960, 1962
    American Antiquarian Society, 1932
    American Bar Association, 1929, 1934, 1935, 1936, 1957, 1958, 1961, 1963, 1966, 1967, 1968
    American Bar Foundation, 1964
    American Business Men's Research Foundation, 1966
    American Geographical Society, 1929, 1955, 1957, 1958, 1959, 1965, 1968, 1969
    American Journal of International Law, 1964, 1966, 1967
    American Judicature Society, 1932, 1933, 1935, 1936, 1962
    American Law Institute, 1931, 1932, 1933, 1934, 1935, 1957, 1964, 1965, 1970, 1971
    American Nature Association, 1947
    American Red Cross, Seattle-King-County, 1933
    American Society of International Law, 1935
    American Society for Oceanography, 1971
    Anderson, F. F., 1958, 1959
    Arakie, David H., 1967
    Armstrong, Charles J., 1959
    Arnold, Thurman, 1941
    Art Institute of Seattle, 1929, 1932, 1933
    Ashley, Paul P., 1931, 1938, 1956, 1958, 1962, 1966